## Ron Mello

ronmellojr@gmail.com 401-226-7180

# **SUMMARY**

Experienced Full-Stack PHP Developer with extensive knowledge of web application development and associated web technologies, coupled with United States Marine Corps leadership experience. Spent over 20 years as a full-time employee of on-site positions as well in distributed environments, while simultaneously 1099 contracting. Adaptable to and flexible in any environment.

## TECHNOLOGY SUMMARY

Programming: PHP, C, C++, JAVA, JavaScript, XML, JSON, ¡Query, AJAX, Bootstrap

DBMS: MySql, SQL, Postgres

Tools: VSCode, Eclipse, PHPStorm, MySQL Workbench, Postman, Git, Notepad++, Jira,

Confluence, Slack

Frameworks: Laravel, Zend, Symfony, Codelgniter, WordPress

Platforms: Ubuntu, Windows

DevOps: AWS (EC2, RDS, S3, Lambda), Kubernetes, Docker, Ansible, CI/CD, Python

Proficient in LAMP technologies, MVC Frameworks and RESTful APIs

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Freelance Contractor

Full-Stack PHP Developer (1099) January 2003 – Present

- Overall duties include gathering requirements with clients, developing code, testing code and ensuring projects are completed on time.
- Able to work unsupervised, under pressure to produce deliverables as part of a team or independently.
- **QMedRx:** Worked with a distributed team of 6 developers for a pharmacy group using Ubuntu, PHP/PostgreSQL, Jasper Reports, Firebird PDO, GIT.
- **Informed DNA:** Worked on a distributed team of 12 developers using Laravel, Vagrant, AWS, Jira, GIT, Slack.
- inMusicBrands: Led the conversion of CodeIgniter systems to Laravel and OctoberCMS.
- **Lenox Property**: Successfully developed a new generation of Laravel PHP applications for real estate, improving agent and admin quality by 50%.
- Participated in RESTful API development and testing with 3rd party vendors.
- WordPress development and customization including eCommerce.
- Linux system administration for AWS, Linode, cPanel.
- Develop mobile applications using the Ionic Framework, Cordova, React.
- Experienced using development tools such as Eclipse, PHP WebStorm, VSCode, CLI.
- Experience with Jira, Trello, GIT and other Agile development tools for project management.
- Experience writing unit and integration tests in PHPUnit.

- Established successful Search Engine Optimization (SEO) and Search Engine Marketing (SEM) campaigns.
- Meticulous documentation of user requirements and system specifications.

### CVS Caremark, Woonsocket, RI

IS Lead Applications Developer, Retail Portal Team (permanent) February 2012 – October 2013

- JAVA enterprise application development with Eclipse, JSP, Spring, Struts, Hibernate, ANT, SVN, SWING GUI.
- Store Systems Support.
- · Learned pharmacy scripting, voluntarily.
- Chosen to lead a planned section of POS system Developers.

# Bradley Hospital/Women & Infants Hospital, Providence, RI

Research Engineer (permanent) September 2004 – September 2006

- Redesign of a kinematics system consisting of IR lights/cameras, and CCTV cameras.
- Design of ECG/Respiration system, encompassing professional digital video and audio.
- Website development.
- Developed MATLAB routines to perform analysis of infant cry signal energies in the time and frequency domains.
- C/C++ routines to post-process various types of physiological data.
- MATLAB used in the post-processing of MRI data sets.

# Raytheon, Portsmouth, RI

Electrical Engineer II (permanent)

May 1999 – January 2003

- Responsible for the development of C and assembly code for farms of TITMS320C4x digital signal processors using Code Composer Studio and the SPOX real-time operating system
- Redesigned C routines to improve performance by 70%.
- Designed MATLAB/C++/JAVA applications to model RF sensor performance.
- Developed C programs for a side-lobe detection algorithm within the signal processing and target identification stages of a system.
- Programming of software packages in C++ for radar system performance modeling.
- Implemented a signal processing discussion group for all levels of expertise to exchange ideas and share technical knowledge.
- Mentored new Engineers joining the team.

#### **EDUCATION**

## University of Rhode Island Kingston, Rhode Island

Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering (BSEE)

Graduated: 1998